By the 1890s, the Spanish Empire was a
到了 19 世纪 90 年代，西班牙帝国已不复往日
shadow of its former self. It had long
荣光。 它早已
lost its great colonies in Mexico and
失去了在墨西哥和秘鲁的大片殖民地，
power [music] in Europe. Its grip on the
在欧洲沦为二流音乐强国。 它对
last remaining vestiges of its empire
帝国最后残余势力的控制
was already slipping. It would take the
已经开始减弱。
United States of America just 3 months
美国仅用了3个月就
imperialism in the Americas to an end.
结束了西班牙在美洲长达400年的帝国主义统治。
This is the story of the
这是美
Spanish-American
西
War.
战争的故事。
Cuba had been growing restless under
古巴在西班牙统治下已经躁动不安数
Spanish rule for decades. Like Mexico
十年。 就像之前的墨西哥一样
before it, Cuba had developed a sense of
，古巴也逐渐形成了
its own identity and pride that could no
自己的身份认同感和自豪感，
longer accept Spanish rule. Spanish Cuba
再也无法接受西班牙的统治。 西班牙统治下的古巴饱受
was plagued by corrupt and incompetent
腐败无能
officials, and Spain simply lacked the
官员的困扰，而西班牙也缺乏
its colonies effectively. [music]
有效统治其殖民地的经济或政治权威。  [音乐]
The Spanish had already put down two
西班牙
waves of rebellion in Cuba in the second
在 19 世纪下半叶已经镇压了古巴的两波叛乱
half of the 19th century, but in 1895, a
，但在 1895 年，
erupted.
爆发了第三次也是更为严重的叛乱。
Despite a consistent weapon shortage and
尽管武器持续短缺，
the deaths of many of its leaders, the
许多领导人也已阵亡，但
Cuban rebels gained massive support for
古巴反叛者仍然获得了广泛的支持
their struggle. The Spanish authorities
。 西班牙当局采取了
reacted with an iron fist. Suspected
强硬手段予以回应。 疑似
rebels were shot on sight. Villages
叛乱分子被当场击毙。
suspected of aiding them had their crops
被怀疑协助叛军的村庄的庄稼被
burned, and entire populations
烧毁，整个村庄的居民
were resettled into towns monitored by
被迁往由
Spanish troops to prevent any secret
西班牙军队监视的城镇，以防止有人秘密
aiding of the rebels.
援助叛军。
Spain was similarly troubled by
西班牙也同样受到
rebellion in the Philippines. The
菲律宾叛乱的困扰。 多年来，这些
islands had suffered exploitation by
岛屿一直遭受
Spain and the Catholic Church for years.
西班牙和天主教会的剥削。
Filipinos were directly involved in
菲律宾人直接参与了
Mexico's fight for independence and
墨西哥的独立战争，并
agitated for their own. In 1896, this
为自己的独立而奔走呼号。  1896年，这
erupted into the Philippine Revolution.
爆发了菲律宾革命。   与
Like in Cuba, Spain reacted with
在古巴一样，西班牙采取了
brutality.
残酷的镇压手段。
Suspected rebels were massacred, and
被怀疑是叛乱分子的人遭到屠杀，
prominent nationalist leaders, most
著名的民族主义领袖，其中最著名
famously the writer Jose Rizal, were
的是作家何塞·黎刹，被
executed by the colonial authorities.
殖民当局处决。
Put simply, by the second half of the
简而言之，到了
1890s, it was obvious that the Spanish
19 世纪 90 年代后半期，西班牙
Empire was on the verge of collapse.
帝国濒临崩溃的迹象已经非常明显。
The empires and kingdoms that lasted
那些延续至今的帝国和王国都是
were run from single chambers, where the
在同一个房间里运作的，
maps, the ledgers, and the advisers all
地图、账簿和顾问都
sat in the same place. The clearer the
集中在一个地方。 画面越清晰
picture, the steadier the rule. That
，规则就越稳固。
principle is what makes today's sponsor
正是这一原则让今天的赞助商
stand out. One dashboard, at
脱颖而出。 在 chat.llm.abacus.ai 上，您可以通过一个控制面板获取
gives you the leading frontier models.
领先的前沿模型。
Chat GPT, Claude, Gemini, Grok, and Deep
Chat GPT、Claude、Gemini、Grok 和 Deep
Seek, plus Root LLM, which automatically
Seek，以及 Root LLM，它会自动
picks the best model for each request,
为每个请求选择最佳模型，
the way a ruler calls on the right
就像统治者召唤合适的
specialist. From there, it does the
专家一样。 剩下的就交给它来完成
rest. Image and video generators like
。 图像和视频生成器，如
Flux and Seed Dance, a presentation
Flux 和 Seed Dance，演示文稿
builder, and Deep Agent, which takes a
构建器，以及 Deep Agent，它可以接收
task and carries it out from research to
任务并执行，从研究到
small apps it can deploy. Connectors
可部署的小型应用程序。 连接器可
link it to Google Drive, Slack, and
将其连接到 Google 云端硬盘、Slack 和
Gmail, and tasks let you schedule work
Gmail，任务功能可让您安排工作
to run on its own, like a standing
自动运行，例如
report every Monday. All of it runs
每周一生成一份定期报告。 所有这些加起来
about $10 a month, far cheaper than
每月大约 10 美元，比
paying for each tool separately. Check
单独购买每种工具便宜得多。 请
using the link in the description and
点击描述和
pinned comment. Now, back to the video.
置顶评论中的链接，访问 chat.llm.abacus.ai 查看详情。 现在，让我们回到视频。
The United States of America definitely
美国肯定
took notice. [music]
注意到了。  [音乐]
America watched the Cuban struggle
美国
especially closely. Given its own
尤其密切地关注着古巴的斗争。 鉴于美国自身的
history, America was naturally
历史，美国自然
sympathetic to its neighbor's fight for
同情其邻国为摆脱
freedom from a distant European [music]
遥远的欧洲（音乐）
power. Washington subscribed to the
强权而进行的斗争。 华盛顿奉行门
Monroe Doctrine on foreign policy, which
罗主义外交政策，
reserved the right to intervene against
保留了干预
any attempts to expand European
任何企图
colonialism in the Americas. While it
在美洲扩张欧洲殖民主义的权利。 虽然它
didn't call for intervention against
没有呼吁对
existing colonies, it was easy to
现有殖民地进行干预，但很容易
stretch the logic. Stories of Spanish
曲解其逻辑。 西班牙
atrocities against civilians made
对平民犯下的暴行
regular appearances in the American
屡屡出现在美国
press, fueling sympathy and outrage in
媒体上，引发了美国民众的同情和愤怒
equal measure, and leading to calls for
，并导致人们呼吁
America to step in.
美国介入。有
Two men bore unique responsibility for
两个人对
the American public's attention on Cuba.
美国公众关注古巴负有独特的责任。   《
Pulitzer, media moguls for the New York
纽约日报》的传媒大亨威廉·伦道夫·赫斯特和《纽约世界报》的传媒大亨约瑟夫·普利策之间展开了
respectively, were locked in an intense
激烈的
fight for sales.
销售争夺战。
In order to capture the public's
为了吸引公众的
attention, they filled their newspapers
注意力，他们在报纸上刊登了大量
with scandalous and often invented
耸人听闻、甚至捏造的
stories, trusting that controversy would
故事，相信争议能够促进
sell papers. [music]
报纸的销售。  [音乐]
It worked. Other papers followed suit,
成功了。 其他报纸纷纷效仿，
and by the late 1890s, the American
到 19 世纪 90 年代末，美国
media landscape was dominated by the
媒体界被
so-called yellow press, which made its
所谓的黄色报纸所主导，这些报纸
money by whipping readers into a frenzy.
通过煽动读者的狂热情绪来赚钱。
The Cuban issue provided endless
古巴问题
material for the yellow press. Stories
为黄色报纸提供了源源不断的素材。  1895 年以后，
of Spanish atrocities against civilians
西班牙对平民犯下暴行的报道
were a regular occurrence after 1895.
屡见不鲜。为了
Eager for even more sensational news
追求更耸人听闻的
stories, the yellow press took an
新闻，黄色报刊采取了
aggressive tone, urging America to
咄咄逼人的姿态，敦促美国动用
intervene with force to protect the
武力干预，以保护
Cubans.
古巴人。
America's interest [music]
美国
in Cuba certainly wasn't all
对古巴音乐的兴趣当然并非完全出于
humanitarian.
人道主义。   将
The idea of acquiring Cuba as another
古巴并入美国成为另一个
state was as old as the Union itself.
州的想法，与美国本身一样古老。
Thomas Jefferson had considered the
托马斯·杰斐逊认为，这座
island the most interesting addition
岛屿是我们国家体系中最有趣的补充
of states. There were still plenty of
。
people in Washington who felt the same
华盛顿仍有很多人抱有同样的看法
There was also significant American
美国对古巴也有着巨大的
economic interest in Cuba. About $35
经济利益。
million of American investments were
美国
wrapped up in the island, and 90%
在古巴的投资约达 3500 万美元，古巴 90% 的
[music]
音乐
of Cuba's foreign exports went to the
出口到
United States. America had a particular
美国。 美国
interest in the sugar and tobacco
对糖业和烟草
industries, which were particularly
业特别感兴趣，而这两个行业又特别受到
affected by the rebellion, since many of
叛乱的影响，因为许多
the plantation workers and farmers left
种植园工人和农民都
to join the rebels. Unrest in Cuba dealt
加入了叛军。 古巴的动荡局势
direct damage to American profits.
直接损害了美国的利润。
On March 8th, 1895, an American merchant
1895 年 3 月 8 日，一艘美国
ship was fired upon by Spanish patrols
商船在
as it passed to the east of Cuba. The
经过古巴东部时遭到西班牙巡逻队的炮击。
Spanish ship had suspected it of
西班牙船只怀疑它向
smuggling weapons to the rebels when it
叛军走私武器，而
had actually been passing from Panama
实际上它只是从巴拿马
back to New York. No one was hurt, but
返回纽约。 虽然没有人受伤，但
American newspapers treated the incident
美国报纸却将这起事件当作
like a declaration of war, running
宣战，刊登
stories declaring that Spain was a
文章宣称西班牙是一个
dangerous and aggressive power that
危险且具有侵略性的强权，
America had a duty to destroy.
美国有责任将其摧毁。
An official Spanish apology and the
西班牙官方的道歉以及
cooler head of President Grover
格罗弗·克利夫兰总统较为冷静的头脑
Cleveland quickly brushed away the
迅速平息了这一
incident, but the warmongering attitude
事件，但
of the American media would only be
美国媒体的好战态度只是
silenced for a little while.
暂时偃旗息鼓了。
President Cleveland was sympathetic to
克利夫兰总统同情
Cuba, but didn't believe America needed
古巴，但他认为美国没有必要
to intervene directly. His
直接干预。 他的
administration rejected calls from
政府拒绝了
American business interests in Cuba to
美国在古巴的商业利益集团要求
intervene to protect their profits. The
干预以保护其利润的呼吁。
administration's position was that the
政府的立场是，这些
businessmen had taken the risk to enter
商人自行承担了进入
Cuba by themselves and had to deal with
古巴的风险，因此必须
those consequences on their own. So long
自行承担由此产生的后果。 只要
as the American people weren't in
美国人民没有处于
danger, there was nothing to be done.
危险之中，就没什么可做的。
April 1896 when an American citizen was
1896 年 4 月，一名美国公民因
caught smuggling weapons into Cuba. He
向古巴走私武器而被抓获，克利夫兰的克制受到了考验。 他
was quickly put on trial and sentenced
很快被送上法庭，
to death two weeks later. [music]
两周后被判处死刑。  [音乐]
Again, the American press exploded with
美国媒体再次群情
anger. The Chicago Tribune urged the US
激愤。  《芝加哥论坛报》敦促
Navy to sail down to Havana and sink
美国海军驶往哈瓦那，击沉
every Spanish vessel there. Instead,
那里所有的西班牙船只。 相反，
President Cleveland appeals to Spain to
克利夫兰总统请求西班牙
spare the man, which they eventually
饶恕这名男子，西班牙最终也
did.
照做了。
Cleveland departed the presidency in
克利夫兰于 1896 年卸任总统
1896, [music] replaced by William
，威廉·
McKinley. McKinley, too, favored a
麦金莱接任。 麦金利也倾向于
peaceful approach. If Spain could be
和平解决争端。 如果能
convinced to roll back its harsh
说服西班牙改变其
treatment of the Cubans, then he would
对古巴人的残酷对待，他就会很
be happy. Direct intervention was always
高兴。 直接干预始终是
an option, but it was one McKinley was
一个选项，但麦金利
reluctant to use.
不愿使用这个选项。
However, McKinley's stance disappointed
然而，麦金利的立场令
many. Press, politicians, and the public
许多人感到失望。 媒体、政界人士和公众
all proposed different solutions to the
都提出了不同的
Cuban crisis.
古巴危机解决方案。
One suggestion was to simply buy the
有人建议直接买下这座
island. If Spain was going to lose it
岛。 如果西班牙无论如何都要输掉这场战争
anyway, wouldn't it make more sense for
，那么
them to accept a few million dollars for
接受几百万美元的赔偿，
it instead of fighting a losing battle?
而不是打一场必败之战，岂不是更明智吗？
Another was to declare full recognition
另一种方法是像美国在 1836 年承认德克萨斯独立那样，宣布完全承认
of Cuban independence in the same way
古巴独立。
This would provoke Spain and create a
这将激怒西班牙，并
justification for America to intervene
为美国干预
to protect the newly independent
以保护这个新独立的
country. [music]
国家创造理由。  [音乐]
Perhaps, as in Texas's case, the US
或许，就像德克萨斯州的情况一样，美国也
could then annex the islands, too.
可以吞并这些岛屿。
1897 when a new government was elected
1897 年 11 月，西班牙选出了新政府，带来了一线希望
in Spain. They promised to scale back
。 他们承诺，
some of the harshest policies if the
如果
rebels were willing to lay down their
叛军愿意放下
arms. They also promised to grant Cubans
武器，就会缩减一些最严厉的政策。 他们还承诺给予古巴人
and Puerto Ricans equal political rights
和波多黎各人与西班牙人同等的政治权利
to those held by Spaniards in Spain.
。
The new government even recalled the
新政府甚至召回了
[music] Cuban Governor-General as a sign
古巴音乐总督，以示
of good faith.
诚意。
The response was disappointing. By now,
反响令人失望。 到现在为止，
the rebels would accept nothing less
叛军绝不会接受任何
than independence.
低于独立的方案。
For the hardline Spaniards in Cuba, it
对于古巴的强硬派西班牙人来说，这
was a betrayal after years of conflict
是对多年冲突
and sacrifice.
和牺牲的背叛。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; McKinley was cautiously optimistic, but
麦金利持谨慎乐观态度，但
he made it clear that if nothing
他明确表示，如果情况没有
improved, action by the [music] United
好转，[音乐]
States will remain to be taken.
美国仍将采取行动。
Nothing much did. War between Cuban
没什么变化。 古巴
rebels and Spanish soldiers continued in
叛军与西班牙士兵之间的战争在
the countryside, and a spasm of riots
农村地区继续进行，1898 年 1 月初，骚乱
tore through major cities in early
席卷了各大城市。
American interests and citizens in Cuba
美国在古巴的利益和公民
were in increasing danger every day.
每天都面临着越来越大的危险。
McKinley had to do something.
麦金利必须采取行动。
"The president has determined to send
“总统已决定派遣
the USS Maine to Havana as a mark of
缅因号战列舰前往哈瓦那，以示
friendship." came the message to Madrid
友谊。”
from Washington in January 1896.
1896年1月，华盛顿向马德里发出了这一信息。
It was a diplomatic excuse that covered
这只是一个掩盖
for the true purpose. The ship was a
真实目的的外交借口。 对于
shield and a sword for Americans in Cuba
驻古巴的美国人来说，这艘船既是盾牌又是利剑，
in case the worst came to pass.
以防最坏的情况发生。
January 25th. Curious crowds came out to
1月25日上午，缅因号战列舰及其355名船员停靠在哈瓦那港。 好奇的群众前来
watch, but there was no protests or
围观，但没有发生抗议或
unrest. The Spanish naval ships also
骚乱。 停靠在哈瓦那的西班牙海军舰艇也对
docked in Havana treated the Americans
美国人表现出了
with forced courtesy, with both sides
勉强的礼貌，双方都
aware that they could be hours away from
意识到，他们可能随时会爆发
open war. It would take the tiniest
公开战争。 只需一丝
spark to light that fire, and fate gave
火星就能点燃那团火焰，而命运却给了
them so much more.
他们更多。
February 15th, an explosion shattered
2月15日晚上10点50分，
the peace at Havana Harbor.
哈瓦那港发生爆炸，打破了平静。
A colossal blast ripped the USS Maine
一声巨响将缅因号战列舰
apart, sending a column of smoke and
撕裂，一股浓烟和
fire 150 ft into the air.
火焰冲天而起，高达 150 英尺。
Most of her 355-man
她的355名
crew was killed instantly. The ship's
船员大部分当场丧生。 船上的
crew quarters, where most of the
船员宿舍，也就是大多数
enlisted men slept, was entirely
水兵睡觉的地方，被彻底
destroyed. Rescuers tried desperately to
摧毁了。 救援人员拼命试图将
pull survivors from the water. Even the
幸存者从水中救出。 就连
Spanish Navy rushed to do what they
西班牙海军也赶来尽力
could to help, but most couldn't be
救援，但大多数人还是没能
saved. 266
获救。  266名
men died.
男子死亡。
It was the biggest single-day loss of
这是自
disaster at the Little Bighorn 20 years
20 年前卡斯特在小比格霍恩战役中惨败以来，美国军人单日伤亡人数最多的一次
earlier. The Maine's commanding officer,
。  “缅因号”的指挥官
Captain Charles Sigsbee, survived. By
查尔斯·西格斯比上尉幸存了下来。 凌晨
1:00 a.m., his message about the
1点，他关于
explosion was in Washington. President
爆炸事件的消息已经传到了华盛顿。
McKinley received the news in his
麦金利总统穿着睡袍接到了消息
dressing gown.
。
Although the captain suspected that the
虽然船长怀疑是
Spanish had caused the explosion, he did
西班牙人造成了爆炸，但他
not point fingers and did not speculate
没有指责任何人，也没有猜测
on what exactly had happened for fear of
究竟发生了什么，以免
inciting a war. "Public opinion should
引发战争。  “在有
be suspended until further report,"
进一步报道之前，公众舆论应该暂停。”
Sigsbee's message said. Those words did
西格斯比在声明中表示。 这些话丝毫
nothing to contain the reaction at home.
没有平息国内的反应。
The yellow press had been handed pure
黄页报业集团简直是捡到了
gold. [music]
宝。  [音乐]
For a week straight, the destruction of
整整一周，
the USS Maine led every newspaper in the
缅因号战舰的沉没占据了全国各大报纸的头条
country. Artists' impressions of the
。 爆炸的艺术想象图
explosion graced every front page. Lists
占据了各大报纸的头版。
of the dead were published for all to
死者名单公之于众，供所有人
see. The New York Journal ran an average
查阅。  《纽约日报》连续数日，平均每天用
of eight and a half pages on Maine for
八页半的篇幅报道缅因州的情况
days on end. William Randolph Hearst
。 威廉·伦道夫·赫斯特
offered a bounty of $50,000
悬赏 5 万美元，缉拿
sent American sailors to their death.
杀害美国水手的罪犯。
The pro-war crowd rallied like never
支持战争的人群
before, crying out for war with their
空前高涨，高呼着
new slogan, "Remember the Maine, to hell
新的口号：“记住缅因号，
with Spain."
西班牙去死吧！”
Modern analysis has concluded that the
现代分析表明，
explosion was likely an accident. A fire
爆炸很可能是一起意外事故。
broke out near the ammunition storage,
弹药库附近发生火灾，
causing a catastrophic detonation. This
引发了灾难性爆炸。
explosion and the conclusion of the
爆炸发生后的几天里，以及
official Spanish investigation. [music]
西班牙官方调查结束后，华盛顿的普遍看法也是如此。  [音乐]
Despite this, the yellow press declared
尽管如此，小报还是宣称
it was surely a mine or torpedo launched
这肯定是西班牙人发射的水雷或鱼雷
by the Spanish. "There was no other
。
option now but war," they said. Many
他们说：“现在除了战争别无选择。” 许多人
agreed. Even Assistant Secretary of the
表示赞同。 就连海军助理部长
Navy Theodore Roosevelt called it an act
西奥多·罗斯福也称这是西班牙人
of dirty treachery on the part of the
卑鄙的背叛行为
Spaniards.
。
McKinley was unable to regain control of
麦金利未能重新掌控
the national mood. As the papers cried
国民情绪。 随着报纸大肆
out for war and public opinion laid
宣扬战争，公众舆论将
blame for hundreds of American lives
数百名美国人的生命归咎于
firmly on Spain, momentum shifted
西班牙，战争的势头
unstoppably towards war.
势不可挡地转向了战争。
Orders were sent out to the Navy. The
海军已接到命令。
Atlantic, Asiatic, and European
大西洋舰队、亚洲舰队和欧洲
squadrons were to ready their sailors
舰队要做好准备，
and stock up on coal, ready to move at a
储备煤炭，随时可以出动
moment's notice.
。
Not a single senator of either party
两党参议员中没有一人
opposed a bill granting $50 million
反对一项拨款 5000 万美元
for the national defense and every
用于国防及
purpose connected therewith. Congress
相关用途的法案。 国会
also made provisions for recruiting
还制定了招募
thousands of new soldiers and providing
数千名新士兵并为
them with arms and equipment.
他们提供武器装备的计划。
US Senator Redfield Proctor returned
美国参议员雷德菲尔德·普罗克特
from a visit to Cuba with tales of
访问古巴后，带回了关于
starvation and mass graves, describing
饥荒和万人坑的故事，称
the native Cubans as being on the verge
古巴土著人民
of total destruction at the hands of
在
Spanish tyranny.
西班牙暴政的统治下濒临彻底毁灭。
Every grizzly detail was eaten up by the
每一个骇人的细节都被
news-reading public. The message was
广大读者津津乐道。 信息很
clear. America was morally compelled to
明确。 美国出于道义有义务与
fight Spain.
西班牙开战。
Over in Madrid, the Spanish government
在马德里，西班牙政府
felt the mood shift. Seeing the change
感受到了这种情绪的变化。 看到
in American attitude and funding, the
美国态度和资金的变化，
peace faction began to gain ground. A
和平派开始取得进展。
war with the United States would be a
与美国开战对
death sentence for Spain's American
西班牙的美洲
empire. But it's no longer mattered. The
帝国来说无异于死刑。 但这已经无关紧要了。 这个
issue was out of Spanish hands. On March
问题已经超出了西班牙的掌控。  3月
28th, the US government's official
28日，美国政府的官方
report blames the sinking of the USS
报告将缅因号战列舰的沉没归咎于
Maine on a sea mine. The evidence was
水雷。 证据根本
nonexistent, and the report couldn't
不存在，而且该报告
even justify pinning it on Spain. At the
甚至无法证明将责任归咎于西班牙。
same time, McKinley's diplomats
与此同时，麦金利的外交官们
escalated to demand full autonomy for
升级了要求古巴完全自治的诉求
Cuba. If Spain did not respond to this
。 如果西班牙不迅速回应这一
request quickly, the US would have to
请求，美国将不得不
take matters into its own hands.
自行采取行动。
The Spanish government [music] dithered
西班牙政府（音乐）犹豫不决，拖延不
and delayed. While the Spanish asked for
决。 西班牙方面要求花
days and weeks to debate the proposal,
数天甚至数周时间来讨论这项提议，而
members of McKinley's own party were
麦金利自己党内的成员却
labeling him a coward and a sellout.
称他为懦夫和叛徒。
"Wall Street [music] doesn't want a war,
“华尔街（音乐界）不想打仗，
and you are doing their bidding." one
而你却在替他们办事。” 一位
angry Republican [music] told him during
愤怒的共和党人（音乐）在访问白宫期间告诉他
a visit to the White House.
。
Final attempts to avert war failed.
避免战争的最后努力失败了。
Austria, Britain, France, Germany,
奥地利、英国、法国、德国、
Italy, and Russia all ordered their
意大利和俄罗斯都命令其
representatives in Washington and Madrid
驻华盛顿和马德里的代表
to appeal to the governments to pull
呼吁各国政府
back, to no avail. On April 10th, the
撤回行动，但都无济于事。  4月10日，
Spanish made the unprecedented decision
西班牙做出了前所未有的决定，
to propose an armistice with the rebels.
向叛军提出停战协议。
Had that decision been made months
如果几个月前就做出这个决定
earlier, the crisis might have stopped
，危机或许就不会发生了
there.
。
But it's was too late. When American
但为时已晚。 当美国
representatives asked if this meant
代表询问这是否意味着
Spain was preparing to recognize Cuban
西班牙准备承认古巴
independence, the Spanish answered with
独立时，西班牙方面
a firm no.
断然回答“不”。
The next day, President McKinley gave a
第二天，麦金利总统
7,000 word speech to Congress. He
向国会发表了长达7000字的演讲。 他
stopped short of asking for war, instead
没有直接要求发动战争，而是
asking for the powers to use the
要求各国以
military in whatever way he saw fit to
他认为合适的任何方式动用军队来
resolve the Cuban crisis. Congress moved
解决古巴导弹危机。
achingly slowly over the next few days
接下来的几天里，国会进展极其缓慢，
as politicians debated the exact wording
政客们就
and limits of America's next step.
美国下一步的具体措辞和限制进行了辩论。
At last, on April 20th, the Spanish
最终，在 4 月 20 日，西班牙
ambassador received a final ultimatum.
大使收到了最后通牒。
Spain had 3 days to announce its full
西班牙有 3 天时间宣布完全
withdrawal from Cuba [music] or America
退出古巴音乐市场，否则美国
would kick them out. The Spanish
将把他们赶出去。
ambassador fled Washington [music] that
当晚，西班牙大使逃离了华盛顿
night. As he packed his things, the US
。 在他收拾行李的时候，美国海军
Navy sent out its ships to blockade
派出舰船封锁
Cuba.
古巴。
the news from Madrid that night.
当晚，西班牙驻古巴总督从马德里收到了消息。
Consider war as declared, hostilities
战争已宣告，敌对行动
will begin immediately.
立即开始。
Congress approved a formal declaration
国会
of war on April [music] 25th. The
于4月25日批准了正式宣战。
government called for 125,000
政府呼吁招募12.5万名
recruits to fill the ranks. Assistant
新兵来填补空缺。
Secretary of the Navy Theodore Roosevelt
海军助理部长西奥多·罗斯福
led by example, quitting his post so he
以身作则，辞去职务，奔赴
could join the war on the front lines.
前线参战。
This video was very interesting to work
制作这个视频的过程非常有趣
on. If you enjoyed it as much as we did,
。 如果你和我们一样喜欢这个节目，请
hit the like button right now and click
立即点赞，并在
the bell before you leave, so you don't
离开前点击铃铛，这样你就不会
miss the next time we uncover history
错过我们下次揭开历史
mysteries. See you next time.
谜团的时刻了。 下次见。